<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.metageek.net"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>MetaGeek blogs</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/news</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en-ID</language>
<item>
 <title>Multi-device support in Chanalyzer 4 and Chanalyzer Pro</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/node/2295</link>
 <description>&lt;br /&gt;Multiple device support added in to the latest updates of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/products/chanalyzer-4&quot;&gt;Chanalyzer 4&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/products/chanalyzer-pro&quot;&gt;Chanalyzer Pro&lt;/a&gt; make it possible to run two or more Wi-Spy DBx or 2.4x at the same time. This allows for viewing multiple swaths of spectrum at the same time from two or more Wi-Spys, be it zoomed-in or full-band in either 2.4 or 5 GHz. Plus, spectrum data from each Wi-Spy unit is collected and saved into one recording.

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/products/chanalyzer-pro&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/files/images/multipledevicecropped.png&quot;  align=&quot;center&quot; alt=&quot;Multi-Device dropdown&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;Just plug the Wi-Spys in, and choose which view you wish to see from the Device Navigator in the upper left corner. Chanalyzer will save the spectrum data from each unit. So keep it running and recording... it will catch RF interference on all the frequency configurations you set and everything will be there for you when you go back to analyze it. And, since it&#039;s all in one recording, making sense of the different spectrum swaths is uncomplicated and eliminates the aggravation of keeping and viewing multiple files.


&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;Multi-device support done simply and effectively. Check it out!</description>
 <comments>http://www.metageek.net/node/2295#comments</comments>
 <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 16:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">2295 at http://www.metageek.net</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Report Builder Preview</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/node/2280</link>
 <description>&lt;div id=&quot;contents&quot; class=&quot;contents&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;report_block&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Report Builder Improved!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_description&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We wanted to highlight some of the cool things you can do in Chanalyzer Pro&#039;s Report Builder. I have written all of this in the Report Builder so you can see how easy it is to create a professional Wi-Fi Spectrum Analysis Report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Chanalyzer now has: text formatting, report continuation, and image blocks.  It is now&lt;u&gt; incredibly easy &lt;/u&gt;to build a professional spectrum analysis report&lt;b&gt; using a mix of recordings and live captures&lt;/b&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;report_block&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Save/Open/Append Options&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;/files/images/save%20report%20options.png&#039;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_description&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;report_block&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Save/Open/Append Previous Reports&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_description&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time is Money, and Chanalyzer Pro saves you both!  Large surveys can require several days and multiple Wi-Spy captures.  
&lt;p&gt;You can now save a report in a special file format specific to Chanalyzer Pro.  This file can be opened later to append your previous work to another capture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;report_block&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Adding Image Blocks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/imageblocks.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_description&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;report_block&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Image Blocks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;/files/images/IMG_20100823_143913%20x600.jpg&#039;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_description&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Chanalyzer Pro&#039;s Report Builder, you can add a camera picture of the source of interference, or the location of the problem area. 

&lt;p&gt;In the MetaGeek interference lab we have a shelf of some common sources of interference in the 2.4GHz band so I thought I&#039;d take a picture and share it with you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;report_block&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Location #1&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;/files/images/ydbpbjrs.zc2_.png&#039;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_description&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select different locations or different recordings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;report_block&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Location #2&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;/files/images/25xwt4lj.sfd_.png&#039;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_description&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.4 GHz 802.11n throughput test.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;report_block&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Location #3&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;/files/images/tv11boug.42j.png&#039;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_description&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;report_block&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Report Builder Blocks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;/files/images/report%20builder%20blocks.png&#039;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_description&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;report_block&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Check out Chanalyzer Pro now!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block_description&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Report generation is very quick.  If you&#039;ve got a Wi-Spy laying around, download a trial of Chanalyzer Pro and give the report builder a try!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for all of the feedback on our software.  More features to come!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://www.metageek.net/node/2280#comments</comments>
 <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Trent</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">2280 at http://www.metageek.net</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Laura Chappell and Wireshark University will host four free webinars Aug 17-19</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/node/2273</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Laura Chappell and Wireshark University will host four free webinars to inform people about the Wireshark Certification Program Aug 17-19.  If interested, please register at &lt;a href=&quot;www.wiresharktraining.com/certification&quot;&gt;www.wiresharktraining.com/certification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free Webinars: About the Wireshark Certification Program&lt;br /&gt;
Instructor: Laura Chappell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These free events cover the process of preparing and registering for the Wireshark Certified Network Analyst Exam. What should you study? How should you study? What are the hot areas on the Exam? What are the Exam question formats? What should you watch for? What if you need to reschedule the Exam? What can you bring with you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A live question and answer session will follow each 20-minute presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://www.metageek.net/node/2273#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/24-ghz">2.4 GHz</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/5-ghz">5 GHz</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/interference">Interference</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/taxonomy/term/424">Laura Chappell</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/news">News</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/press">press</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/wi-fi">Wi-Fi</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/taxonomy/term/423">wireshark</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/wlan">WLAN</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 00:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">2273 at http://www.metageek.net</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Use Your Waterfall View to Answer &quot;Why?&quot;</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/node/2231</link>
 <description>&lt;b&gt;Use Your Waterfall View to Answer &quot;Why?&quot;&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was tinkering with a Java-based Graphical frontend to Iperf called &quot;JPerf&quot; and I thought it would be cool to visually show how data being pushed through the physical 2.4GHz band looks like in Chanalyzer Pro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was primarily interested in seeing how a microwave oven will affect data throughput.  When running the throughput test I turned the microwave oven on.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Wi-Spy with my little ..er.. Wi-Spy, microwave interference!&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too bad these views tell you little about the cause of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldn&#039;t it be nice if you could zoom into this point in time to see what happened?  With Chanalyzer Pro you can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/throughput_test_using_iperf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Narrow in on the Waterfall View for those Details, Details, Details!&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the source of your troubles is just a click away. Notice how the first highlighted box on the left still represents the Iperf graph above. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/time%20segments.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Time Segment A&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I started the throughput test there were some APs broadcasting beacons in HR-DSSS modulation.  These are represented in Chanalyzer Pro&#039;s Density View as curved shapes hovering over a Wi-Fi Channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/pre-transfer.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Time Segment B&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a time segment where throughput was at its highest.  We can see that the AP on channel 1 jumped to 802.11n 40MHz-wide channel bonded transmission.  In the density view high activity is represented by brightness.  The colors are very bright for the 802.11n broadcast.  We can still see the curvature of the AP on Channel 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/normal-transfer.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Time Segment C&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We no longer see the curvature of the access point on channel 11. A hill of activity ranging from channel 6 to channel 13 appears where we once saw the AP.  The Wi-Fi on Channel 1 appears less bright and the shape is less defined indicating something changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/microwave-transfer.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Tell them Why!&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a deliverable to visually explain the complexities of interference.  &lt;a href=&quot;/downloads/Chanalyzer%20Pro%20Sample%20Report.pdf&quot;&gt;See a sample report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
 <comments>http://www.metageek.net/node/2231#comments</comments>
 <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 22:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Trent</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">2231 at http://www.metageek.net</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title> Metageek Releases Chanalyzer Pro Software, the Industry&#039;s Only Professional Spectrum Analysis Software for Windows 32, 64-Bit</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/node/2213</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;MetaGeek&#039;s new software companion to Wi-Spy, Chanalyzer Pro, includes a Wi-Fi Report Builder, Device Finder and Device Identification. Available now, Chanalyzer Pro is compatible with Wi-Spy 2.4x and the dual-band Wi-Spy DBx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boise, ID July 28, 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MetaGeek, developer of wireless network diagnostic tools, has released &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/products/chanalyzer-pro&quot;&gt;Chanalyzer Pro&lt;/a&gt; for the Wi-Spy line of USB Spectrum Analyzers. New features include Wi-Fi report generation that gives network administrators a detailed snapshot of the current interference situation-useful in both pre-deployment WLAN planning and post-deployment RF spectrum management. Chanalyzer Pro not only identifies what types of devices are interfering with your Wi-Fi networks, it also helps users track down the offending devices with its new Device Finder mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Chanalyzer Pro takes your Wi-Spy and knocks it up a notch&quot;, says Ryan Woodings, Chief Geek at MetaGeek. &quot;We took the feedback from previous Chanalyzer versions and developed Chanalyzer Pro from the ground up into a professional, powerful and robust tool that&#039;s just as easy to use as our other software.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlighted Features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report Builder: easily generates powerful reports for documenting interference problems and explaining them to non-technical decision makers. Exportable to HTML, RTF and PDF file formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Finder: enables the user to track down an RF transmitting device by graphing signal strength over time. This is further aided by MetaGeek&#039;s new purpose-built Directional Antenna (available in September for $69).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Identification: identifies RF signals by device type, giving the user an idea of what kind of devices are causing interference in the vicinity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated User Interface: new waterfall time frame playback controls allows the user to graphically navigate through collected spectrum data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Price and Availability&lt;br /&gt;
Chanalyzer Pro is available now as an upgrade ($499) for current Wi-Spy 2.4x and DBx owners. It can also be purchased as part of a bundle with Wi-Spy DBx ($999) or Wi-Spy 2.4x ($599).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About MetaGeek, LLC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based in Boise, Idaho MetaGeek develops troubleshooting tools for wireless network administrators including the award-winning line of Wi-Spy spectrum analyzers. www.metageek.net&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://www.metageek.net/node/2213#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/24-ghz">2.4 GHz</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/blog">blog</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/chanalyzer-pro">Chanalyzer pro</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/interference">Interference</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/metageek">MetaGeek</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/news">News</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/press">press</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/spectrum-analyzer">spectrum analyzer</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/wi-fi">Wi-Fi</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/wi-spy">Wi-Spy</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 22:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">2213 at http://www.metageek.net</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>What !? 500 Wi-Fi connections will cause interference?</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/blog/what-500-wi-fi-connections-will-cause-interference</link>
 <description>If you haven&#039;t heard or seen by now, Steve Jobs of Apple fame had quite the embarrassing moment demoing iPhone 4 features over Wi-Fi at the WWDC event this week. Anything Wi-Fi catches our attention here at MetaGeek, and an epic Wi-Fi fail involving one of the tech industry&#039;s major players, well, how could we ignore that.!?

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;object width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;340&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/znxQOPFg2mo&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/znxQOPFg2mo&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;340&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=znxQOPFg2mo&quot;&gt;video clip&lt;/a&gt; Jobs exclaimed at one point &quot;There are 570 Wi-Fi base stations operating in this room...and several hundred of these are those MiFi things, by the way&quot;. Now, I&#039;ve never been to the Moscone Center for an Apple event, but I&#039;ve experienced a similarly over-crowded 2.4 GHz spectrum at the Interop show in Las Vegas--and Wi-Fi just. plain. doesn&#039;t. work. So, although half of me winces with empathy for Mr. Jobs--since I too have had wireless fail me at inopportune times--the other half screams... &quot;YOU SHOULD HAVE KNOWN BETTER!&quot;

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;I&#039;m probably preaching to the choir writing this on the MetaGeek blog, but this reminds us all of a very fundamental and inescapable fact; the Wi-Fi bands are only so big and only have room for a finite (really quite small) number of transmitters. When signals overlap and transmit on the same frequencies, neither signal will have optimum throughput capability because they will be interfering with each other. In Apple&#039;s extreme case, the 500+ access point connections (and most certainly non-Wi-Fi gadgets like Bluetooth devices) brought in by the event attendees, rendered the 2.4 GHz band essentially unusable. I&#039;m sure that Wi-Fi wasn&#039;t working that well for anybody in the room, whether it was a blogger, journalist or member of the Apple crew. This, at it&#039;s core, is why spectrum analyzers--like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/products/wi-spy-dbx&quot;&gt;Wi-Spy&lt;/a&gt;--are essential in making Wi-Fi work as it should. Spectrum management is paramount in maintaining a solid, fast and reliable WLAN.

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;Was there a lesson learned? I&#039;m sure that with Apple&#039;s wireless network crew there most certainly was. And, I would venture to say at the next demo event, Apple will have all sorts of free, high-speed 5 GHz networks set up for the blogger types to use in lieu of their own 2.4 GHz hotspots to help &quot;spread out&quot; spectrum usage. Also, it would not surprise me if there&#039;s some sort of spectrum police keeping 2.4 GHz open for Mr. Job&#039;s demo devices only...

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;So, Apple, if you&#039;re listening, I know of just the tool to keep an eye on your wireless spectrum. Drop me a line at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mark@metageek.net&quot;&gt;mark@metageek.net&lt;/a&gt;, I can hook you up.. :-)</description>
 <comments>http://www.metageek.net/blog/what-500-wi-fi-connections-will-cause-interference#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/24-ghz">2.4 GHz</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/apple">Apple</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/interference">Interference</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/iphone">iPhone</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/jobs">Jobs</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/mifi">MiFi</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/news">News</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/press">press</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/spectrum-analyzer">spectrum analyzer</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/wi-fi">Wi-Fi</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/wireless-interference">wireless interference</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/wlan">WLAN</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 05:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">2147 at http://www.metageek.net</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Chanalyzer Pro: Click and Drag to Zoom Frequencies</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/blog/chanalyzer-pro-click-and-drag-zoom-frequencies</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The hardware configuration features in Chanalyzer 3.4 were cool, but required too many settings to zoom into arbitrary frequency ranges... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chanalyzer Pro zooming frequency to look at a specific signal is as easy as click-and-drag. If there&#039;s a weird signal next to your Wi-Fi just click on one side of the signal, drag the mouse across the signal to the other side and let go and Bam! Chanalyzer Pro automatically adjusts its frequency settings to zoom into the signal you&#039;ve highlighted. Here&#039;s a quick video showing it in action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/blog/chanalyzer-pro-click-and-drag-zoom-frequencies&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
 <comments>http://www.metageek.net/blog/chanalyzer-pro-click-and-drag-zoom-frequencies#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/news">News</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 21:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>ChiefGeek</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">2129 at http://www.metageek.net</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Co-Channel Interference Video using Chanalyzer</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/blog/co-channel-interference-video-using-chanalyzer</link>
 <description>&lt;object width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;385&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/vLJSuqWBzlY&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;hd=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/vLJSuqWBzlY&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;hd=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;385&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stumbled across a great youtube video demonstrating co-channel interference.  He is using Iperf as a throughput utility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/blog/co-channel-interference-video-using-chanalyzer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
 <comments>http://www.metageek.net/blog/co-channel-interference-video-using-chanalyzer#comments</comments>
 <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 16:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Trent</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">2107 at http://www.metageek.net</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>MetaGeek Announces Chanalyzer Pro Spectrum Analysis Software for Wi- Spy, Adds Device Classification, Device Finder</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/blog/metageek-announces-chanalyzer-pro-spectrum-analysis-software-wi-spy-adds-device-classification-</link>
 <description>&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;MetaGeek&#039;s new software companion to Wi-Spy, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/node/2040&quot;&gt;Chanalyzer Pro&lt;/a&gt;, includes sought-after features including device classification, device finder and automated reports. Available June 30, 2010, Chanalyzer Pro will be compatible with Wi-Spy 2.4x and the dual-band Wi-Spy DBx.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/blog/metageek-announces-chanalyzer-pro-spectrum-analysis-software-wi-spy-adds-device-classification-&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
 <comments>http://www.metageek.net/blog/metageek-announces-chanalyzer-pro-spectrum-analysis-software-wi-spy-adds-device-classification-#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/24-ghz">2.4 GHz</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/5-ghz">5 GHz</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/chanalyzer-pro">Chanalyzer pro</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/interference">Interference</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/news">News</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/press">press</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/spectrum-analyzer">spectrum analyzer</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/wi-fi">Wi-Fi</category>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/wlan">WLAN</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 14:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">2069 at http://www.metageek.net</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Chanalyzer Pro: Sparklines</title>
 <link>http://www.metageek.net/blog/chanalyzer-pro-sparklines</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;We&#039;ve been working for the past few months on some really nifty innovations for Chanalyzer Pro and I thought I&#039;d share some of these concepts with you to get your feedback. The first concept is pretty simple... we&#039;ve added &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sparkline&quot;&gt;sparklines&lt;/a&gt; to the Wi-Fi table. This makes it easier to see at a glance if a network&#039;s signal strength is consistent or is bouncing up and down. In the screenshot below the MetaGeekGN network has a consistently strong signal, while GemStatePaper is weaker and more inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metageek.net/blog/chanalyzer-pro-sparklines&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
 <comments>http://www.metageek.net/blog/chanalyzer-pro-sparklines#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://www.metageek.net/category/content-tags/news">News</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 23:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>ChiefGeek</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">2068 at http://www.metageek.net</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
